<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on Kahoy documentation</title><link>https://docs.kahoy.dev/introduction/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on Kahoy documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://docs.kahoy.dev/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting started</title><link>https://docs.kahoy.dev/introduction/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kahoy.dev/introduction/getting-started/</guid><description>Prerequisites A Kubernetes cluster and access to it. Install Kahoy. Install Kubectl. Path to a group of Kubernetes YAML manifests. Install Kahoy Get latests binary release from Github.
Use Kahoy We are going to use Kubernetes provider, this means that it will store kahoy&amp;rsquo;s execution state on Kubernetes.
Our Kahoy state will be identified by ci id and stored on default namespace. Our manifest YAML files are on .</description></item><item><title>Alternatives and scope</title><link>https://docs.kahoy.dev/introduction/alternatives-and-scope/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kahoy.dev/introduction/alternatives-and-scope/</guid><description>Alternatives Kahoy born because available alternatives are too complex, Kubernetes is a complex system by itself, adding more complexity in the cases where is not needed, is not a good solution.
Helm: Tries solving other kinds of problems, has templating (v2 tiller), the concept of releases, used to deploy single apps&amp;hellip; However, you can use helm for templating and kahoy to deploy the generated manifests. Kustomize: Similar scope as helm but with a different approach, like Helm, you can use kustomize for the templating and kahoy for deploying raw manifests.</description></item><item><title>Features</title><link>https://docs.kahoy.dev/introduction/features/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kahoy.dev/introduction/features/</guid><description>TODO</description></item><item><title>Installing Kahoy</title><link>https://docs.kahoy.dev/introduction/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.kahoy.dev/introduction/install/</guid><description>Releases You have ready to be used binaries in Github releases.
To get the latest release, grab it here.
Docker In case you want to use Docker, you have a ready to be used image on docker hub, this image has Kahoy and some dependencies like kubectl and git.
docker pull slok/kahoy Build from source You can build binaries from source easily.
git clone git@github.com:slok/kahoy.git cd ./kahoy make build</description></item></channel></rss>